welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
okay check-ins I feeling kind of like
giddy playful every time I'm in Joe's
presence I feel like I want to be a holy
fool so and then that's the I mean that
is the best compliment possible so
welcome to the stoah I am Peter limber
Stewart of the stoah and the Stowe is a
place for us to cohere and dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of this moment and today we have my
my very good friends from human systems
I've taken one of their courses their
introductory courses and it was fucking
brilliant I'd loved it I think I
understand most of it and I want to
learn more about it so that's why I'm
eager to get the human systems people
here to kind of like display their magic
and and share it and spread it as far
and wide and if I can help that then
it's an honor for me to do it so I don't
really know what the sessions gonna be
about I read the copy and then me and
Anne were like just kind of like talking
when I was sort of in a dark night of
the soul last week so I don't really
know much about what's going to happen
in this session but I have full trust
that it's gonna go well so that being
said I will hand it over to Anne who's
gonna be the emcee for the evening and
she's gonna explain what's gonna happen
today ah I'm unmuted
hello I love you people I feel a bit
nervous and then I just looked at all
the pictures I see so many people I
haven't seen in a while and and I feel
really happy I'm so nervous
but also happy and I'm with you in
systems maybe Joe Nathan and Sarah you
can wave yes the people who are waving
right now we're with human systems and
we're doing a thing tonight we call it
life action redesign which we've done a
few times before in our kickoff calls
it's the beginning of our class usually
where we kind of show what
we think put together it could look like
and we've never done it and such a big
public setting just exciting
nerve-wracking and I'm gonna give you a
quick overview of what's gonna happen
next
70 minutes Joe's gonna tell you a few
things about human systems Sarah's gonna
tell you a few things about how you
could be here and then Nathan and I will
interview one volunteer after you've you
submitted ideas of what we could
redesign today before end and you read
through them and we will interview one
person and kind of articulate what the
value at the core of their story might
be that might have been really difficult
to live by and then Nathan I will
disappear and Joe and Sarah will guide
you through two different games
depending on your preference tonight
after which we come back and show you
what we came up with and then there's
time for Q&A and then we go sleep or
half-day depending on the times when we
win Joe what's human systems about hi
everybody this is cool some of you know
so I apologize I'm gonna take a few
sentences to tell you stuff you already
know we work on redesigning things
around values most of our society is
designed around metrics goals norms
complying with the way that people
usually act or like norms like
professionalism or goals like maximizing
profit this kind of stuff and we have a
kind of a shortage of systems that are
designed around values and often the
systems that are designed around goals
or norms are they they block our values
they make it harder to be creative or
playful or honest or however we actually
want to be with the people in our lives
so that's what we teach is just a simple
thing about figuring out what people's
values are and how to redesign the
systems of our lives
organizations birthday parties dinner
family dinners up to social networks
earlier today I helped redesign a
difficult family dinner arrangement and
a social network but according to values
so that's what we do and that's kind of
what we're gonna demonstrate today and
will also play a few games that show
just give you a kind of clue about how
we do that
hopefully the demonstration will be
you'll be like wow I wouldn't have
thought about how to redesign that
myself and if you do have that reaction
then we can help you learn to redesign
things the way we do cool I guess I talk
now so I want to give a couple of things
to keep in mind while you're here to
help you get the most out of it because
this is actually gonna be pretty
participatory the first part where we've
taken a couple of submissions before the
column we've chosen one person that
we're gonna do a redesign for and so the
human systems members will be asking
them some questions to get the
information they need to do the redesign
but we'll also be asking you what sort
of questions would you need to do this
we design because afterwards you're
going to get the chance to split into
groups and one of the groups is going to
try their hands at doing redesigns too
so the first rule this is to keep your
brain on think about like what
information would you need to know to
redesign systems and also maybe keep in
mind a system of your own and just kind
of call this to mind right now like if
you had expert help what situation in
your life do you feel is not letting you
live in the way that you want to because
we have this really different world with
quarantine and I was I was just on a
call with Google earlier where you know
some of the people were like um you know
eating more than I want to or I'm kind
of having trouble having meetings where
I can feel really connected to people
what are the what's one thing you're
struggling with and and you can kind of
use that as a reference point as we play
these games and do these redesigns
and the other part of this is we get a
unique opportunity to be creative on
this call so think about you know you
might have your solutions for how you
usually do things or how you think about
them and maybe just start questioning
like what are other ways of doing this
as you hear the questions that are being
asked what if you apply those to your
situation and if you get if you're in
the group that's doing a redesign what
are different ways to think about it
it's not first thought best thought is
great but we're actually looking for
your second and your third and your
fourth thoughts as well so I'll hand it
back to Joe I think sake hot potato hand
it to me Joe hand it to me passing it's
an okay this has a hundred percent of
our pre talk we're done with the pre
talk now we do the actual thing which
means that Nathan and I are gonna
interview one of you and we got a few
submissions and we just checked in with
that man I don't actually know how to
say your name is left man right yeah
[Music]
in ones across interviewing him it's
Inayat thank you for that and maybe just
like and give me like 20 seconds to
gather my thoughts on us yes was
probably years ago when I was working
about ten people in a small business in
Melbourne and I discovered when I was
working there like that one of my
colleagues was moonlighting and trying
to you know him and two other people in
the business we're planning to steal a
whole bunch of clients and set up her
rival business
and I felt real being betrayed and and
disappointed
particularly at one of the guys that was
doing this because he was one of my
friends so I yeah I I confronted him
about it I said you know you should be
doing this I can get some you know
it hurts me and it hurts everyone else
in this business and yeah I just don't
think you should be doing it and he made
me feel like I was the person that was
betraying him because I was threatening
to tell the boss and if I did that then
I would be harming him because I would
you know be causing him to lose his job
so he made me feel like I was the one
that was being unfair and it it wasn't
right for me to do that so he said you
know you should you know it doesn't
really matter because these clients are
really small that we're trying to poach
and you know the bosses are under paying
you and everyone else in the business so
it doesn't matter like you know why are
you doing this to me it's really unfair
like don't don't do this to me so I was
putting a really awkward decision
because I valued my friendship with this
guy previously I really enjoyed hanging
out with it but he really made me feel
just kind of well because I wanted to
preserve my friendship with him but I
also didn't want the business to fail
and didn't want that habit negative pick
on me thank you
ya know but they like the rest of the
story or like wow actually what happened
what did you do it well actually like I
end up doing absolutely nothing I like
it really
I read deliberated over for a long time
but I just did nothing and I regretted
not doing that because eventually the
whole situation unraveled because he
sent him emails who is I think like
Chris who is the other co-conspirator
and he accidentally cc'd everyone in the
business and revealed like the whole
thing
so it was yeah like basically shit hit
the fan and as you say I guess we didn't
stay in Australia and like the his whole
couple was blowing and you know the
situation unraveled anywhere so I really
liked what I you know what I realized
that I should have done at that point
it's just like I should have told the
boss anyway you just pointed out like
several things that you kind of felt and
said we'd overcome there's like a lot of
people involved unlike a lot of swords a
lot of people and some of the things
that I picked out was something like
angry towards your friends and then
something sounded like maybe like a bit
disoriented so I'm not quite sure what
to do
well my was I felt betray and yeah he's
appointed
did you ever think afterwards about what
you wish you had been able to do in that
situation
yeah I really wish that I had the
courage and integrity to to actually
report the situation to my boss because
I really valued put a lot of trust in me
and I yeah I really felt that I had kind
of no no that boy yeah because I wasn't
I didn't have the confidence actually to
say what was going on yeah if you had
had the make you feel like you had had
some kind of courage and integrity in
that situation and you maybe would have
like gotten up your courage to talk to
your boss and your friendship with your
friend is still kind of in chatters and
maybe it doesn't even really help
wouldest would it have been worth it I
think it would have been because I think
that's I think that I think that I could
have I think that I could have salvaged
a relationship with a friend even if I
did turn you mean actually because I
think you know I could have I could have
said to him okay you know I'm giving you
an option you can is doing this anymore
and I won't report you to the boss or
you can keep doing what you're doing and
I was like I should give you that
ultimatum then maybe his decision as to
what he wanted to do what
I'm Nathan hi can you say more about
like the way that this company was set
up like you had clients yeah they were
running like the guy the boss is the guy
that started to come
and hired you guys on to help deal with
these clients that gun more and more how
did that work how do you just get built
up sure yeah the company was started by
two guys and then it grew to enable and
it was a marketing agency so we had like
quite a large number of clients and you
know a elaborate scheme to try and to
try and steal the clients where they
would register domain names that were
very similar to the clients domain names
so then they could send emails through
the clock to the business pretending to
be the clients so they could spoof email
addresses so it looked like there's an
email coming from the client
it was actually an email from an email
address that had like one letter
different so they create this quite
elaborate schemes to try to try and
trick the owner of the agency to think
that the clients were leaving the agency
when they weren't there actually like
you know they they were going to this
other business of they were setting up
on staff so they were telling one thing
to the clients and saying alright
alright you know the the business here
is closing down but you know we're
starting on this new businesses you can
go over to eat with us now and meanwhile
to the boss they were saying oh we lost
his client oh here's the email you can
see it wasn't like your friendship to
the to these guys who like kudos for the
scheme was he your friendship with them
that seemed to have like blocked you
from from saying something about it or
was there were there other factors
involved that like made you think who
was the ringleader this is like yes the
one guy who organized better the whole
thing his name's Chris and he's and I
never really liked this guy anyway but
he yeah so Chris started the whole thing
and then he tried to recruit other
people my other colleagues into the into
this games world
so it wasn't my relationship with Chris
that I cared about it was my
relationship with one of the guys in
this inspiringly so you know this guy
called Tim like he you know he like it
was really his idea it was just going
along with it so I didn't consider him
as guilty as the guy who organized the
whole thing but yeah what's this like I
wonder like in this workspace did you
have with this like the one time that
you kind of felt like you weren't able
to like show up with this courage and
integrity or were there other moments
that like we're all so difficult no I
always felt like I was able to to work
with integrity and an honor and tell the
truth this is the first time that I've
encountered that yeah okay so it's one
of the it's because of his friend
essentially yeah yeah it was just you
know I was just worried about losing
this friendship because yeah and the
other thing that made it quite difficult
is like you know my friend said to me I
hey you know this is this isn't a big
deal what I'm doing because the bosses
are under paying you and there are under
paying everyone else they're making all
this money and because I didn't have
access to you know any of the finances I
didn't know whether I was being
underpaid or not so I had to kind of you
know maybe I am being screwed over by
the boss here so maybe maybe you
actually consider this but I didn't want
to if you could go back now and talk to
yourself when you're in that situation
like what did what advice would you give
to yourself I would say you don't have
to worry about losing your friendship I
because the friendship
was already lost anyway like I I felt
betrayed by him so I didn't want to be
his friend so I really didn't have
anything to lose by telling the boss
what was happening I mean did you know
that at the time I'm kind of wondering
what would you say to yourself if you
were to like try to maybe this is a
different question but again if you were
to like sort of advise yourself like
where are you in a situation like that
right now what kind of thing would you
try to focus on what would you like to
pay attention to to figure out what to
do what would I pay attention to I guess
or outs of what I value more whether I
value my friendship with my work
colleague or whether I value having a
secure job and a secure income whether I
maybe not maybe not to do with the
secure income thing maybe whether I
value being able to tell the truth um
you just mentioned like two or maybe
three things that are kind of like hard
of living with this courage and
integrity in that particular situation
mm-hmm
one of them is maybe something like
doubt maybe they're right maybe you act
in screwed over by your boss in some
kind of like mourning something that's
already lost yeah and then third one's
maybe like some kind of like weighing of
different importances if these three
things had worked out would you have
been alright well actually so what are
the three things the 'i like maybe your
boss is really screwing you over maybe
they are right yeah not quite seeing
that like a thing is already lost and
trading off different and different
interests different goals yeah well I
never found out whether the owners of
the business word
screwing us all over and I actually did
manage to salvage my friendship so yeah
I guess some if I had found out that it
was true then the bosses were screwing
us all over then I guess I would have
been okay with it I mean maybe like the
thing I'm curious about is if those if
all of that had been easy like some
magic trick would you have been alright
would it have made it possible to have
the curse integrity that was difficult
or is there more what do you mean
[Music]
if in that situation those three things
by some solution had been possible yeah
like you you you're absolutely sure that
you're not being screwed over you fully
aware that this friendship is kind of
lost in some way and it's clear to you
that the job is more important than the
friendship would that have been enough
for you to feel at ease
encouragement integrity yeah because the
biggest thing I was worried about was
the friendship and I didn't believe that
the the the friendship was lost so if I
knew that I didn't have to continue
being friends with this person then and
I was totally comfortable with that then
yeah I would have had no problem living
up to that value at least I think I
would it still would have been a very
awkward conversation with my boss but I
think I would have had the courage to do
it
I just had to look at the there's like
some of the questions in the in the chat
they just like check them out and one of
them is what about the relationship with
your friend made it hard to confront him
honestly
hmm yeah I guess I I guess I needed this
I guess I needed to be friends with him
more than he needed to be friends with
me because I was you know it was a
difficult period of my life when I was
living in Melbourne I didn't have that
made friends so you know and I was going
through a transition year period where
I'd like I'd broken up with my
girlfriend and I'd like you know so I
had like a dramatic loss of friends and
yeah I'm really worried a lot at that
period of my life what other people
thought of me you know that's always
been a part of my personality like I
care you know I worry too much what
other people think of me certainly more
than other people I think in this
situation what does the what was the
worry how might they how my days to you
what was I worried about Tim saying me
yeah oh how he might see you oh how he
might see me
I'm not sure
yeah I guess I didn't want people to see
these desperate or lonely well actually
if I if I confronted him I was worried
that like I was worried that if I
confronted him then he would see me as
callous and cold-hearted and me because
I was you know potentially causing him
to be fired so yeah I didn't want to
meet a lot of his Callison : yeah when
in fact that's kind of what he was
saying it is what he was saying when you
were like in a situation that called for
this kind of integrity or courage that
you managed to pull it off yeah yeah I
mean I can think of situations where
like you know I've been you know my
twenties when I was like like I can
think it's a great number of had friends
who are really and they wanted to you
know like you know like the situation
where my friend Michael was really drawn
are like and he wanted to follow me to
this bar that I was going to and I just
you know wrestled him into an uber
because like because I just didn't want
him to to continue to hang out with me
on that night so I can yeah that's more
about like in that situation like what
kind of things were you paying attention
to what were you focusing on when you
decided like I'm gonna wrestle you into
this uber this isn't happening
yeah
well I was thinking about myself really
like I I just didn't I wasn't thinking
about like what he could do to other
people like whether he would I don't
know whether he would offend anyone else
I was just really sick of his company so
it was all just about me really like I
was like I dunno see you anymore like go
away I think that's what matters I
wasn't thinking about what other people
I wasn't thinking about he's affecting
other people I was thinking about he's
affects on me can I take a stab I think
what like what one value in this in this
cloud of important things might be yeah
if it's like somewhat about boundaries
or like about something like taking care
of your like taking care of yourself
with people you love acknowledging that
they might not be acting as they wish
they might have acted or like with some
like with a slight hint of forgiveness
or something you may
I wish my friends had I'm not sure what
you mean by that I'm sorry no worries
that's good didn't mean start mean on it
so here's the thing I'm trying to do we
just kind of like talked a bit of audio
story and the emotions that came up in
it and kind of what was difficult what
was the situation like and there's a
bunch of different kinds of information
we're trying to kind of filter out of
that which you'll see again later how
they come back there's one very specific
kind of formulaic thing that I'm looking
for and that is kind of the thing that's
important in the situation that's
difficult and I think we're very close
to it like there's something about
integrity about honesty I think there's
something about like boundaries or like
like asserting yourself some kind of
assertiveness and I'm mostly just kind
of like trying to zoom in on like the
particular neurons of it like what
exactly is this kind of assertiveness it
was hard here and they said do you have
a question on yeah is there like so is
there somebody that you think would have
handled this kind of situation well no
somebody specifically not just like
theoretically but you know like my sorry
taxi was my best friend my second best
friend would absolutely have if he was
in my situation in the business with Tim
he absolutely would have told us because
he are you so like beyond like sort of
what he would have done like how would
he have approached that situation what
would he have been like focused on how
would he have approached that situation
ah he would admire about like how he
approaches situations like that yeah I
really admire he doesn't care whether
what other people think of him and it's
yeah he has no real care for the
consequences yeah because I worry about
consequences all the time so much that
it stops me from actually doing anything
so yeah so it's kind of something around
like doing what you think is right
without regard to the consequences are
there are other people's opinion of you
nice cool here's what's gonna happen
next I'm gonna disappear we're not
actually going to appear we're gonna
turn off the camera
mute ourselves and you're in a sauna
we're just gonna do things and you're
you're all are in good hands with Joe
and Sarah and what Joe and Sarah will do
with you they will explain to you now
thank you so we're gonna play while they
redesign I guess maybe business which is
kind of a cool challenge like - how
would you make this is something that we
can all think about while well Ana
Nathan work like how would you if you
were starting a business and you didn't
want stuff like that to happen you
wanted your employees to to be able to
do what's right to have this kind of
integrity and so on how would you design
that business differently than that
business was designed that's kind of the
big problem that we'll be solving today
and I think it's really good one in a
good like showcase of what we do so
while they do that we're gonna split it
up up into two groups and Sarah is gonna
run something and I'm gonna run
something I'm gonna run something
emotional and Sarah is gonna run
something cognitive because I'm an
emotional person and Sarah is a
cognitive person yeah that seems true
I wasn't authentic relating and
emotional Joe okay so I the way we're
gonna do this is I would love it if
you'll see at the bottom of your screen
there's a little reactions button so if
you want to be in the emotional group I
want you to do the clap sign and it but
you don't have the clap sign I'm gonna
assume you're gonna be in my group which
is obviously the better group which is
like and we're gonna see how this goes
um if you yeah you can just put clap and
chat um
so give me a second and Joe could you do
me a favor and read off the names that
have claps next to them that would help
me a lot yeah sure so Steve in the UK is
clapping there's a lot of claps I feel
very popular Peter is clapping now is
clapping below he says click more I
don't know what that means
Chris is clapping Salma Hoff is clapping
Paul and his clapping Travis man is
clapping Megan Cavanaugh is clapping
James Baker is clapping Steve UK is
clapping I said that before
you know Neil's is clapping yo Keem
doesn't understand what it means to clap
we'll have to teach him
Branden Feingold is clapping yeah
clapping is joining the group that's
gonna be working on emotions an
emotional game and I'm gonna be doing
something that's more like actually we
designed the system yourself below Oh
Tanya is now clapping yo Keem decided
clap last
yeah char is clapping and I think that's
it great
all right the best year with me and okay
so I'm gonna open it Mac team might have
been clapping and Lily Higgins sorry
there's some stragglers okay I think
I've got most you okay cool um so I'm
gonna open y'all are gonna be in
breakout room 1 and I believe that
you're gonna be back in about 20 minutes
so Joe we've got a little bit less time
than was planned originally very not 22
maybe so like half past all right so
rooms are opening the rest of y'all will
stay in here with me hey y'all so we're
going to try something and this is gonna
be a bit of an experiment in full
disclosure I joined human systems rather
recently so I'm still learning their
practices as well although I do some
similar things on my own and we've never
tried to have a group just do a redesign
on their own without going through the
class but I thought it would be a really
cool experiment to have us do the same
thing that they're going away and doing
and so I'm gonna teach you one more of
the tools that human systems uses and
then I'm gonna break you into groups of
about four people each to try your hand
at it we design and so what we're gonna
do first is we're gonna do something
called structural features and that is
if you go to the notes stock that Bilal
posted I'm gonna post this in chat again
because this has notes on it which you
might be able to use for your redesign
one of the things you also see in there
is a
structural features document I'm gonna
put in a shot as Wow cool so so
basically like when we do a redesign the
first thing that we try to do is
identify what happened in a situation
and then what value the person was
holding because everyone everyone like
cares about different things in the
situation right like for Lachlan what
his value was basically like I would say
to something like staying committed to
this like higher ideal that he holds
regardless of the consequences but for
someone else
the ideal might be something like making
sure that they stay true to their
standard of integrity or respecting
friendship or you know there's there's
many different ways and and to do a
redesign we need to understand what we
need to keep in mind because if we do a
whole redesign and it doesn't actually
keep in mind that value like then it's
not gonna be effective for him might be
effective for whoever did that we design
so the other thing that we that helps us
do these redesigns is thinking about
what are the features of the situation
that are unique so the the graph the
chart the chart posted gives some of
these and there might be others as well
and so what I want to invite is we're
gonna try to put in chat what are things
that were characteristics of the
situation with Lachlan that could maybe
be changed an example of one might be
that the interactions were just going on
between him and his coworker so we call
that instead of being the size was like
you know a small number of people so 1 2
1 imagine what the situation might have
been different if instead Lachlan like
gathered a whole group of his co-workers
to talk about it together that's one
thing that could be changed
so one structural feature is group size
are there any others feel free to put
them in chat if you're if you're kind of
understanding this at all
anonymity if who submits the report
like what if it had been public what
things could you change lack of clarity
and transparency so yeah something like
who holds the information any others
they don't have to be from this list but
yeah norms around who you can ask for
advice what would actually what I love
about that is like what were the roles
of people on the team and was that
they're like did you have a confidant
you could go to for instance
expectations about value alignment where
their norms so you see like as we give
these there's like lots of different
things when they got the type of
hierarchy could you go to the managers
easily for instance we don't know the
depth of the relationship maybe the
depth of the relationship with his
friend versus with other co-workers or
with other people in town like a
redesign could be make friends outside
of the company and then come back to the
situation so you're not gonna lose so
losing that friend isn't this big great
so what we're gonna do now and you can
keep putting these in chat if you want
to but I'm going to put each of y'all
into groups of four people and since
some people have kind of been dropping
in and out you might be in groups of
three that's fine as well
but each group is going to when you get
into your group change choose one
feature that you'd like to work on and
try to spend as little time as possible
choosing a feature and then you're gonna
see if you can redesign the situation
based on changing that feature so for
instance if the feature that you're
choosing and and try to choose you can
try to choose something that's a little
bit easier so like ownership of the
company
definitely one might be a little bit
harder to change something like like you
know depth what I was just saying like
you have that this person is a good
acquaintance so where else could you
find depths of friendship if it wasn't
with that person what might be a
redesign what can you change the depth
of friendship with this person or make
yourself less dependent on them what's
the quality of relationship with other
people and you're not gonna have all the
options obviously because you're not
Lachlan unless you have them in yours
group in which case you kind of win so
you can kind of like make up some of the
details if you don't have them cuz part
of this is just really a chance to try
your hand at this and you're gonna have
about 10 minutes or so to try doing a
redesign and my suggestion is for the
first four or five minutes of that just
bling storm like all the things you can
imagine changing about this feature all
the creative you know ways you can play
with it if you want to step outside the
future and like you know suggest some
other redesigns that's fine too but I
find this the feature like helped sway
my thoughts so it's not just this big
unknown and then for the next five
minutes I'll send you a message when you
can stop playing storming or if you stop
before that that's fine for the next
couple of minutes you're gonna figure
out which of those options might be best
keeping in mind Laughlin's value so if
his value that we've identified is doing
what you think is right without regard
without holding in so high regard what
other people think of you like having
what is right at the top does that
effect at all which sort of solution
that you choose and I'm gonna put that
in chat again just so everyone has it
handy and it's in this document great um
you actually will have access to the
chat and the breakouts you won't be able
when you go into breakout so you can
still see everything that's been posted
in chat thus far but when you're in the
breakout if you post something in chat
the whole group won't see it only your
breakout group will see it so just keep
that in mind if you want to make
comments that the whole group can see
maybe do it on the document and then
we'll come back we'll give you a minute
or two to share your redesigns as well
any questions on this I know it's a
little bit complicated and when you're
in the group you can be
your hand if you get stuck you lead a
question yeah I was wondering if you
could just repeat the values again and
then maybe slight expansion on the idea
of like the idea of not wanting to care
so much what other people think of you
yeah the idea that that's not a value
even though it's still exerted force in
his decision-making process to me seems
a bit wonky I wonder if you just clarify
that bit I values are aspirational so if
the value Lachlan held was I want to do
what's right without regard to
consequence there was something that was
blocking that out you like he could hold
it in the situation of like getting his
friend into an uber but he couldn't hold
it in this situation so what we're
trying to do is remove some of the
impediments to him holding his value
okay a question um so again you're gonna
choose one structural feature and you're
going to try to redesign the situation
by changing that feature in such a way
that it's easier for Lachlan to live by
his value let's give it a try if you get
stuck feel free to just raise a hand and
I will pop in and help you out so I'm
just gonna do for a second so please
hold and while you're holding feel free
to take a look at the chat and think
about which of those features you might
particularly want to fuck around with
almost there
all right you also be getting invited to
join the room so feel free to do that
one of yous gonna have four people or
should Sarah just again quickly we were
in the room with a twist Joe is it I'm
not sure but there's three of us that
got moved to like another breakout room
for some reason oh sorry about that
me it's Nils I think was Travis - oh
okay sorry about that oh shit sorry I
fucked this up
I have never tried to do this in quite
this way before and I just completely
screwed it up so give me just a second
to fix that well throw our names in the
chat box no it's actually everybody okay
noise I tried to move people from the
breakout rooms or the other one instead
of the other way around
so everyone should be back in there now
oops okay so this is how we do it I need
to assign you all there we go that
should do it
[Music]
alright did y'all get oh you didn't all
get assigned alright we make that happen
and look an extra person eat chickpeas
Nils and Travis did you get the invites
back to the breakout room one with Jo oh
that's weird
it has you in there I don't know how do
we invite you so let me try to figure
that out just a second yeah it should
can you click that that is weird
can you do me a favor and oh there we go
and then Nathan me back here you muted
can you onion you
you sure did you just leave and come
back again yeah I had to restart my
computer okay what when were you in the
emotional I guess okay can I actually go
to the other one please if possible then
not emotional one um there unfortunately
already in breakouts so you can go back
to them to the first room or you can
hang out here until folks get back in
about six minutes yes I made the
emotional one please if you would thank
you you are welcome to go feel your
emotions I'll do my best
oh okay you should be in like everyone
okay
well I am so curious what this thing is
I'm gonna tell you hi
were you in the room earlier wait are
you just joining us I was just on my
phone and I got into a breakout group
but then I got um when I try to turn
they're exciting but I was in breakout
group seven Oh everybody back actually
I'm sorry that you got kicked out of
that I'm excited to hear what yeah same
I'm about to bring up you but be back
let me close the rooms and we're gonna
have lots of people talking back on and
I believe what we're gonna do is have
folks report from the breakout groups
first and then have you double one
you're gonna have a little bit less time
and then you thought like maybe five
minutes
Scot I want a full report after this is
what you thought
all right welcome back everyone so the
trainers are gonna present their
redesign but first I'd love to just hear
a couple highlights anyone who wants to
share from either grave upscale like for
four minutes or so to take a couple of
shares so you can unmute yourself if you
have something you did yeah I'll share
something so myself and Rhys were in a
room together and we chose the feature
of expectations around a value alignment
across cases so like how do you know
what's an emergency state where you have
to have a different orientation what's
the balance of all your values and we
didn't come up with full fledged
solutions but we identified some
features that are worth thinking about
of that feature so one is that
essentially you might not be able to
always hire people with perfect values
but you essentially want people to know
their own belly so you can have a
transparent discussion around how value
orientation is going to change during
emergencies and sort of like during you
know more serious cases and so you know
you could you could basically facilitate
that you could facilitate conversations
with employees that that allow them to
understand their own value set and and
have that sort of like marriage process
between them and the company going on
forward and then you could have an open
and transparent conversations about what
qualifies an emergency State a state
where people begin to have a different
balance an orientation towards balance
between their different values and there
was a couple of other items but I'll
skim past them because they have less
detail okay thank you you Lee um so we
were in the group that cheated and got
Lachlan and one of the structural
features that we were looking at was
group size in this company it was about
10 people as I said the contractors were
basically working by themselves and look
said they meant that it felt like he
couldn't share his concerns with other
people because he hadn't wasn't able to
build up those relationships with other
people in the company and so we're
proposing that if instead of most
contractors working by themselves they
worked in a group of three that when
this problem came up he would have this
group that he had already built quite a
lot of trust with from working on
existing projects and he could have not
only brought it to them and discussed it
with them but if they agreed then they
could be his allies in confronting their
a friend so let's let's get just one
share from Joe's group and if you all
had other solutions you came up with
around structural features please feel
free to put them in the chat or in the
document and then we'll house our
trainers present there's someone from
Joseph Joe you can call him someone of
you maybe Lily or Tonya could go because
they both seem to have a good time and
they didn't talk about sure um yeah
actually I was
I got a lot from Lily chair and she was
noticing that there are sort of these
external things that she was doing when
she was trying to seem to be in
alignment with a value that she had
versus when she was just wanting like to
be that way on her own terms it felt
like Oh like I don't it was less of a an
active thing I noticed it seemed to be
more about sort of creating the
conditions in myself for that value to
emerge where is the one I'm trying to
I'm seeming trying to seem like I'm that
way it feels more like I'm performing
and externally it's more of an active
external it could be performing yeah
I'll just say a word of explanation
which is like our exercise for those who
didn't do it was about looking at the
difference between how we
act 2 seem certain ways so like norms
that we comply with and how oxen our own
terms which is often revealing of our
personal values so it was a exercise
about starting to look inside and see
where we're operating from our values
we're not
and ours identified the features of a
situation that might be blocking the
value and then had people do redesigns
changing different features so now I
want to bring our trainers back and and
Nathan so that they can give us some
ideas of what they came up with and you
can see what every design looks like yes
it's Nathan's here are you here Nathan
so we just this was like like a pressure
cooker
whoo and we did the following we we had
basically like a few questions in mind
as we thought about laughlin story I'm
gonna quickly recap it because he did
other things in between maybe you had
amnesia and you don't know anymore what
I'm talking about so that I worked in a
company relatively small time people and
one of his colleagues was also at that
time was a close friend actually one of
his closest had a scheme to kind of like
steal clients from the company which
sounded like a bad idea but also kind of
detrimental to the feeling of safety in
his job and he found it difficult to
speak to his boss about it and didn't
and later wish he had so he's what I did
the value that we kind of articulated
out of that was crawling up where did I
put it yeah doing what you think is
right without regard of the consequences
or what other people think of you and I
asked myself what's really hard about
that why is it difficult to do for
laughlin why would it be difficult to do
for me and I'm asking that because by
looking for the points that are really
difficult I can then think about how to
make them easier so basically I look for
the breaking
poins why are people unable to do this
thing that they really care about and in
asking that I found a bunch of things
and some of them are kind of
surprisingly long-term they don't
actually have anything to do with the
situation of talking with your boss or
your friend but they start like years
earlier so here here we go
I'm scrolling down again and my
incredibly long document so one of the
things that's important to do is kind of
like having a clear feeling about what
is right for you and that might involve
questioning and improving your
understanding of what is right
evolving it over time and one one little
game idea that I had how to address this
is you could kind of like invite a few
friends over for dinner and together you
hunt for moments of uncertainty for
things that you didn't quite know how to
do and you play them through together
and you just spend evening thinking
through the things that you you were
struggling making a Colin and figuring
all together what a good car would have
been for you to kind of take the intense
pressure off the situation out and have
more time to do the same thing with a
bit more leisurely
low-stakes another really big batch of
stuff that's super hard to do about this
value is reframing and building
friendship asking what is friendship
awards and how do I make the kind of
friendship I really want to have in my
life and one thing in particular that I
think I would find hard in the Helens
situation is to keep along and what by
it wide here's the German coming through
long and wide view of friendship in mind
so both keep in mind what kind of
friendship do I want to have with this
person over the next 10 15 years but
also what kinds of friends do I want to
have in my life and I think one way I
would address that as to give that on
like an audio meditation to meditate on
what friendships he wants and this
process the sadness of not having that
right now and checking and whether he
has hope to actually make that possible
or talk to a friend who's 10 15 years
older and ask what friendships they
really cherished and how they got them
into their life
mmm cool I'm gonna skip these and then I
think another batch of stuff that's
really hard is in the conversation
itself to notice when Lachlan kind of
gets out of what he thinks is right into
some kind of other mode and find his way
back and this is like a gigantic batch
of things that people find hard in a lot
of scenarios and
I thought about the best way to fix that
is to change the context of the
conversation which is my Chi to pass
over to me right so Lachlan could have
changed a number of things about how
this conversation was taking place that
would have made it easier for him to to
do what he thought was right regardless
of the consequences or what people
thought of him one of them is that he
there was a status thing going on he was
being approached as a co-conspirator
against the boss and so like you're in
in the in-group here and he could have
named his agency saying something like
that's a pretty strange move that you
tell me about your COO before you've
pulled it off like you might be the guy
who's trying to sync my job just to name
that like he's not in this group and he
could have there was there evidently it
seemed like these conversations were
taking place in a really brief time like
people were kind of like just on the
side talking about it so he could have
said after having established his agency
and removed himself from this sort of
like co-conspirator role he was being
portrayed in um could have invited the
other people who wanted to do this - a
weekend getaway with all of the
potential co-conspirators and instead of
the pretext of goals which they had like
well we could make more money you're
getting screwed these kind of things he
could have changed that to be about a
shared value this weekend getaway is
about how would we want to do business
so and in that context it would have
been with without being part of this
conspiratorial group having named his
agency having had a longer time to talk
and making the conversation not about
what are we gonna do but how do we want
to be in business it would have been a
lot easier for him to speak to what he
thought was right this would have just
like made it made it a like cleared a
lot of the obstacles out of the way for
him so yeah those are what we call
structural features you guys worked on -
but that's what I came up with for that
and now I hand it back over to Sarah or
and I guess that's all I have to say
I'm gonna hand it to Joe actually to
close us out with a little bit about how
to do more of this a lot of handing
going on I have hands so this has been a
little demo of what we do something that
I would love to if we had a little more
time with that redesign I would love to
try to wrap those hard steps that Ann
mentioned of living by this value and
those structural feature changes that
Nathan mentioned and wrap them up into a
like a business structure like so that
if you were starting a business with a
small team you know how would you end up
having shared values like Nathan was
saying how would you end up making these
hard steps easier for your employees or
for everyone working with and and if you
were able to do that as part of your
business as part of the structure of
your business then you would have a
business in which the value that that
locky wanted to live by was easier in
that business and so that's kind of what
we do we figure out how to make values
easier to live by in different kinds of
social systems at different scales
ranging from yeah like I said family
dinners to capitalism and democracy and
if you would like to do that like do
these redesigns and learn all this
terminology and this kind of stuff we
teach classes or if you know something
like an oppressive social environment
we're also starting to get into
consulting or at least thinking about it
we have a whole bunch of alumni we've
got 300 alumni that have taken our
classes that are ready to help redesign
systems that are suppressing values in
different ways so whether you want to
learn it yourself or feel like you could
use help from this kind of redesign you
can get in touch with us and I guess
Peter will send you links and Sara will
send there's a we have like a form that
you can use that she'll drop in to chat
and we'd love feedback about this event
actually this is the first time have you
done it
[Music]
in front of an audience like this and
we'd love to do it again and if you have
something that your now that you've seen
how it works you're like oh I'd like to
see how they would redesign you know my
situation you can fill out that form and
we'll do this again soon and maybe we'll
pick your situation anything I forgot to
say I dropping the feedback form you
just talked about into the chat and I'm
putting a link to human systems
organization if you click through that
you can find a form to sign up for the
class to register interest conversation
and I also want to name this is the
first time that we've done this sort of
thing outside of the class so definitely
feedback welcome and yeah thank you so
much for showing up and participating in
the games and the redesigns thank you
for choosing my example how did we do
how is it for you to have this happen oh
yeah it was really humbling it was it
was really particularly like Nathan's
suggestion to name that I was the group
like because it realized like they were
trying to make me feel like position me
as a co-conspirator and then I was
obligated to to go along with the whole
things are I am I never thought about
that
so thank you Nathan all right so I'm
gonna jump in so I want to respect the
time of the space so I'll make some
closing announcements I just wanted to
thank Joe Sarah Nathan and and for
coming in today and kicking some ass I I
took the human systems course I highly
highly recommend it it was like a nine
sessions of fun and adventure and it's
very hands-on so definitely want that
website link human systems and check it
out and then Joe there's a wisdom gym
that's forming here at the stove we have
reoccurring events we have about 12 so
far I would love for human systems to
have something on a regular basis a
weekly basis we could do this every week
if you want to and so you have my full
trust and it's open for
you to explore an experiment and have
fun so oh yeah and I would also
recommend because I love Joe's writing
he check out his medium page right here
is a lot of richness there so yeah next
events we have two coming up today we
have a shame breakthrough boot camp with
AJ bond and I think he's doing like a
narcissistic spotlight event again where
everyone's like cameras goes off and
stepped one person we just kind of like
talk about you know what we don't want
to be seen how we want to be seen it was
delicious last time and then we have
that so that's 6 p.m. Eastern Time at
8:30 p.m. user time we have an
existential dance party with Colin
Morris that might get changed to Sunday
but you know if you're interested RCP
and if there's a bulk of people then we
might keep it yeah and we have my my boy
Tyson's in the crowd today and he says
there's something called freestyling
through a pandemic Tyson could you
unmute yourself and let us know what
that's about
sure freestyling through a pandemic is a
freestyle rap experience open to all
levels of skills so whether even if
you've never free thought before common
deep in your relationship with
uncertainty with musicality with rhythm
in poetry and with each other I'm having
so much fun in these spaces and I'm
always really enjoy being surprised by
myself and others when we just open up
and we let the words happen and we let
the music flow through it's been a
really wonderful and I look forward to
flowing with you there yeah and that's
under the website to stow uh dot CA you
can do all that it has a really fuckin
good event if you ever want to like put
yourself with a nice edge you just like
yeah oh yeah it's really good really
good check it out
lastly the Stowe is based off a gift
economy I'm viewing it as a gift for all
of us to use in this time of need if
you're inspired to give a gift to the
stoah just go to the website the store
does see and check out the gift economy
at the end of the page or everyone
thanks so much for coming out today